Guide to the Humanities Council Records RG.9.5.1
New York University Archives
- Series II: NYU Programming, 1976-1995; 13.75 Linear Feet in 28 manuscript boxes, 3 half-manuscript boxes, and 17 folders in oversize flat boxes; 4.9 Megabytes in 221 computer files; 2 VHS; 17 Quarter_Inch_Audio_Reel; 95 audiocassettes
  - Subseries II.C: Visiting Scholars Programming, 1977-1992; 6.5 Linear Feet in 12 manuscript boxes and 8 folders in oversize flat boxes; 9 Quarter_Inch_Audio_Reel; 44 audiocassettes; 188.4 kilobytes in 80 computer files
    - David Miller--"The Future of Socialism in the Advanced Societies", 1986
      - Audio Recordings, February 18, 1986
        - Audio Reel -- 2 of 2 (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0282)
        - Audiocassette (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0098)
    - Constantine Trypanis--"Sophocles' Oedipus at Colonus", 1986
      - Paper Records, 1986 (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Audio Recording, April 15, 1986 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0151)
    - Roger Penrose--"Infinite Jigsaw Puzzles and Quasi-Crystals", April 22, 1986 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0152)
    - Joan W. Scott--"Is Gender a Useful Category of Historical Analysis?", 1986
      - Paper Records, 1986 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Poster, 1986 (Box 88, Folder 10)
      - Lecture, April 30, 1986 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0153)
      - Seminar with Graduate Student Forum, May 1, 1986 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0155)
    - Raymond Carr--"The Spanish Civil War: Fifty Years Later", 1986
      - Poster, 1986 (Box Shared University Archives 154, Folder 1)
      - Audio Recordings, March 4, 1986
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0157)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0158)
    - Daniel de Coppet--"Melanesian Big Men: Hierarchy and Social Control", 1986
      - Paper Records, 1986 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - Poster, 1986 (Box 88, Folder 10)
      - Audio Recording, May 1, 1986 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0154)
    - Xiao Qian--"Memoirs of a Chinese Intellectual", October 6, 1986 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0160)
    - Sir Curtis Keeble--"British Relations with the Soviet Union", October 15, 1986 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0161)
    - Gerald Holton--"The Nascent Phase of Scientific Work", November 11, 1986 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0101)
    - Sir Ernst Gombrich--"The Language of the Eyes", November 17, 1986
      - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0102)
      - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0103)
    - John Price Gaventa, February 11, 1987 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0097)
    - Gerald Alymer--"Post Imperial Hangover? British Influences in the Making of the United States Constitution", April 6, 1987 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0091)
    - James Billington--"The Millenium of Christendom in Russia", December 15, 1987
      - Audiocassette (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0076)
      - Audio Reel (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0072)
    - J.R. Pole--"The Uses of Antiquity in the Debates over Ratification", 1988
      - Flyers, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 16)
      - Audio Recording, February 23, 1988 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0227)
    - Francis Haskell--"The Historian and the Visual Arts: A Problem of Identity", 1988
      - Paper Records, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - Poster, 1988 (Box 88, Folder 10)
      - Audio Recordings, March 17, 1988
        - Audiocassette (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0228)
        - Audio Reel (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0281)
    - Sir Peter Ramsbotham--"The Art of Diplomacy", April 25, 1988 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0230)
    - Jonathan Schell--"The Political Legacy of Vietnam", 1988
      - Poster, 1988 (Box Shared University Archives 155, Folder 4)
      - Audio Recordings, November 10, 1988
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box Shared University Archives 151, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0233)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box Shared University Archives 151, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0237)
    - David Bromwich Lecture, April 12, 1989 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0252)
    - Chinua Achebe--"Restoring Celebration to African Literature", 1989
      - Paper Records, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - Poster, 1989 (Box 88, Folder 10)
      - Audio Recordings, April 13, 1989
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0250)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0251)
    - Fergus Millar--"Popular Politics and the End of the Roman Republic", September 19, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Yirmiahu Yovel--"Spinoza: The Marrano of Reason", 1990
      - Paper Records, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 10)
      - Electronic Records, 1990; RG_9-5-1_ER_75
    - Sir Raymond Hoffenberg--"Two Approaches to Medical Care: The U.K. and the U.S.", March 21, 1990 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0272)
    - Kofi Anyidoho--"Poetry as Performance: The African Experience" -- Poster, November 8, 1990 (Box Shared University Archives 155, Folder 4)
    - A Reading by Anthony Cronin, Distinguished Irish Poet, 1990
      - Paper Records, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - Poster, 1990 (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Arthur Hertzberg--"Zionism Reassessed: A Century Later", 1991
      - Poster, 1991 (Box Shared University Archives 097, Folder 14)
      - Audio Recording, March 18, 1991 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0129)
    - Arnold Rambersand--"African-American Lives: Biography an Autobiography", 1991
      - Paper Records, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 11)
      - Audio Recording, March 21, 1991 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0126)
    - Robert Farris Thompson--"Kongo Carolina, Kongo New Orleans: Notes on a Major Transatlantic Art Tradition" -- Poster, April 16, 1991 (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - George Steiner--"Sombre Hopes", 1991
      - Paper Records, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 12)
      - Poster, 1991 (Box 88, Folder 10)
      - Audio Recordings, April 22, 1991
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0123)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0124)
    - Fernanda Pivano--"My Friend, Ernest Hemingway", October 8, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Arthur Hertzberg--"The Jewish American Community: A Troubled Elite", 1991-1992
      - Electronic Records, 1991; RG_9-5-1_ER_34
      - Poster, 1991 (Box 88, Folder 10)
      - Audio Recording, September 17, 1992 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0009)
  - Subseries II.D: Lectures, 1977-1994; 3.75 Linear Feet in 7 manuscript boxes, 1 half-manuscript box, and 5 folders in oversize flat boxes; 13 audiocassettes; 3 Quarter_Inch_Audio_Reel; 220.5 kilobytes in 22 computer files
    Subseries II.D Lectures (dated 1977-1994) includes files related to lectures and lecture series the Humanities Council organized at NYU. Files for individual lectures or series include varying combinations of records, including correspondence, logistical planning information, invitations, mailing lists, the text of lectures, and event scripts. This subseries also contains posters advertising visiting lectures and audio recordings of some events.
    - Comparative Literature Lecture Series, 1977-1978 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Lecture Proposals, 1977-1984 (Box 30, Folder 2-12)
    - Writers at Work Lecture Series, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Presidential Lectures, 1981, 1992-1993
      - Kriser Presidential Lecture Series, 1981 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Tony Judt--"What is Left of the Left? Post '89 Dilemmas in Historical Perspective", 1992
        - Paper Records, 1992 (Box 35, Folder 14)
        - Audio Recordings, December 12, 1992
          - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0167)
          - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0176)
      - Lea Brilmayer--"The World's Policeman?", 1993
        - Paper Records, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 15)
        - Electronic Records, 1993; RG_9-5-1_ER_60
        - Audio Recording, March 31, 1993 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0032)
      - Sylvia Molloy--"Lost in Translation: Fictions of Latin America", March 8, 1994 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0023)
    - Bayard Still Lecture on Greenwich Village, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - Galileo Lecture, November 6, 1982 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0039)
    - 13th Annual National Endowment for the Humanities Jefferson Lecture: "Humanities and Defense of a Free Society" Sidney Hook, 1984
      - Paper Records, 1984 (Box 43, Folder 3-5, Box 44, Folder 1-2)
      - Electronic Records, 1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_65
      - Audio Recording, May 17, 1984 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0208)
      - Poster, 1984 (Box Shared University Archives 155, Folder 5)
    - Lecture Posters, 1984-1988 (Box 88, Folder 10, Box Shared University Archives 154, Folder 1)
    - Two Lectures by Breyton Breytenbach--Poster, February 6-7, 1985 (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - Medieval Renaissance Society Lecture Series Posters, March-May, 1985 (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - Psychology Lecture Series: Irving Stone--"The Science and Art of Biography" -- Poster, 1985 (Box Shared University Archives 155, Folder 4)
    - Artists at the Institute Lecture Series, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - 10th Anniversary of the Humanities Council Lecture: "Writer and Public" By Saul Bellow, December 4, 1986
      - Audiocassette (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0100)
      - Audio Reel -- 1 of 3 (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0279)
      - Audio Reel -- 2 of 3 (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0278)
      - Audio Reel -- 3 of 3 (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0280)
    - Constitutional Lecture Series: Richards and Dworkin--"Political Theory, Founders' Intent, and Constitutional Interpretation", 1987
      - Posters, 1987 (Box 88, Folder 10, Box 29, Folder 16)
      - Audio Recording, November 8, 1987 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0075)
    - Humanities Council Lectures Planning Files, 1987-1989; RG_9-5-1_ER_54
    - Museums and National Identity Lecture Series, 1987-1988
      - Paper Records, 1987-1988 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - Poster, 1987-1988 (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - John Hope Franklin--"A Life of Learning", April 14, 1988 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0229)
    - Father Daley Lecture Series on the 25th Anniversary Vatican II, November, 1989 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Reverend Wyatt Tee Walker--"Music and The Black Church: Reflections of the African American Experience" Lecture and Performance, 1990
      - Paper Records, 1990 (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Audio Recording, May 3, 1990 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0263)
    - Charles Homer Haskins Lecture: "Life of Learning" by Paul Oskar Kristeller, April 24, 1990 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0105)
    - Joint Lecture Series on Jewish Art with Union College, 1990-1993 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Albert Romasco Memorial Lecture: Ronald Takaki--"Asian and Irish Immigrant Women", 1991
      - Poster, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Audio Recording, November 4, 1991 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0026)
    - Asya Berger Mairead Maguire Talk at Ireland House, February 14, 1994 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0013)
  - Subseries II.E: Medical and Dental Schools Programming, 1978-1992; 1 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and 2 folders in oversize flat boxes; 5 audiocassettes; 20.5 kilobytes in 11 computer files
    Subseries II.E Medical and Dental Schools Programming (dated 1978-1992) contains paper and electronic records of interdisciplinary humanities events tailored to medical and dental students. Files for each lecture or event include varying combinations of records, including correspondence, logistical planning information, invitations, mailing lists, the text of lectures, brochures, and posters. This subseries also contains audio recordings of some events.
    - Medical School Honors Lectures, 1978-1985
      - Barbara Tuchman--"The Humanities for Everybody", 1978 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - June Goodfield and Helen Yglesias--"Imagining a Life in the Medical World: Two Writers Reflect", 1982
        - Poster, 1982 (Box 88, Folder 8)
        - Audio Recording, January 25, 1982 (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0173)
      - Gerald Holton--"The Scientist's Work and the Historian's Task", March 22, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Sir Andrew Huxley--"Accident and Design in Scientific Discovery", May 24, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Thomas Nagel--"Subject, Object, and the Mind-Body Problem", 1982
        - Paper Records, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 3)
        - Poster, 1982 (Box 88, Folder 8)
      - Charles Rosenburg Lecture on the History of Science and Medicine, December 13, 1982 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0054)
      - Peter Bergman--"The Physicist as Artist", 1983
        - Paper Records, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 4)
        - Poster, 1983 (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - Regina Morantz--"Daughters of Aesculapus: Women Physicians in American Medicine", April 18, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - The Great American Medicine Show Lectures, 1983
        - Paper Records, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 6)
        - Poster, 1983 (Box 88, Folder 8)
        - Audio Recording, September 28, 1983 (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0169)
        - Electronic Records, 1983; RG_9-5-1_ER_31
      - Wassily Leontief--"The Economics of Health Care", 1984
        - Paper Records, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 7)
        - Poster, 1984 (Box 88, Folder 8)
      - A. Richard Turner--"Blood and Bones: Leonardo Looks Inside", 1984
        - Paper Records, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 8)
        - Poster, 1984 (Box 88, Folder 8)
        - Audio Recording, March 28, 1984 (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0171)
        - Electronic Records, 1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_33
      - E.L. Doctorow--"How Writers Write", 1985
        - Paper Records, 1985 (Box 35, Folder 9)
        - Audio Recording, February 25, 1985 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0218)
    - Dental School Lecture: Elie Wiesel--"The Ethical Aspects of Contemporary Literature", 1979 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Ways of the Hand: An Exhibition of Fine Handiwork and Art Contributed by Members of the Dental Community--Poster, October 20-25, 1980 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Humanities Discussion Groups for the Health Center Community, 1983, 1987
      - Electronic Records, 1983; RG_9-5-1_ER_55
      - Paper Records, Spring 1987 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Malvin Ring Dental School Lecture, April 1984 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Undergraduate Seminars for Medical and Dental Programs, 1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_72
    - Awakenings Film Screening, November 30, 1992 (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - Subseries II.F: Conferences and Symposia, 1978-1995; 2 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes and 5 folders in oversize flat boxes; 24 audiocassettes; 5 Quarter_Inch_Audio_Reel; 15.7 kilobytes in 7 computer files
    Subseries II.F Conferences and Symposia (dated 1978-1995) contains files documenting the planning and execution of conferences and symposia arranged by the Humanities Council. The files include paper and electronic records, including proposals, correspondence with participants, logistical planning information, invitations, mailing lists, and posters. This subseries also contains audio recordings of some events.
    - Academic Advising for the Humanitites Conference, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Comparative Literature Conference, 1978-1980 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - History of Power and Sexuality Conference, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Ontology and Reference in Contemporary Italian Poetry Symposium, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Culture in the Metropolis: Paris/New York 1990/1980 Symposium, April 16, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Origins: A Centennial Appraisal of Charles Darwin Symposium, 1982
      - Paper Records, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - Audio Recordings, April 19, 1982
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0040)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0052)
    - Brooklyn Bridge Bicentennial Symposium, April 21, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - St. Francis Symposium, October 5-6, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 11, Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Jewish Publication Society New Bible Translation Symposium, May 16, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Proposed Irish Symposium, 1983, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - The Nature of the Mind Symposium, 1983
      - Paper Records, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - Poster, 1983 (Box Shared University Archives 154, Folder 2)
      - Audio Recordings, April 7, 1983
        - Audio Reel -- 1 of 3 (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0064)
        - Audio Reel -- 2 of 3 (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0065)
        - Audio Reel -- 3 of 3 (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0066)
        - Audiocassette -- 1 of 4 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0047)
        - Audiocassette -- 2 of 4 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0048)
        - Audiocassette -- 3 of 4 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0057)
        - Audiocassette -- 4 of 4 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0058)
      - Audio Recordings, April 8, 1983
        - Audio Reel -- 1 of 2 (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0067)
        - Audio Reel -- 2 of 2 (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0068)
        - Audiocassette -- 1 of 3 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0049)
        - Audiocassette -- 2 of 3 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0056)
        - Audiocassette -- 3 of 3 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0059)
    - Social Education in the U.S. and Japan Conference, May 1984 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Bronislav Malinowski Centenary Conference, 1984
      - Paper Records, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Poster, 1984 (Box 88, Folder 12)
      - Electronic Records, 1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_36
    - War and Aesthetics Symposium -- Poster, November 9, 1985 (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - The Exercise of Power: Perspectives from Humanities Symposium, 1987
      - Paper Records, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 15)
      - Poster, 1987 (Box 88, Folder 9)
      - Audio Recordings, May 15, 1987
        - Audio -- 1 of 11 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0077)
        - Audio -- 2 of 11 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0078)
        - Audio -- 3 of 11 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0079)
        - Audio -- 4 of 11 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0080)
        - Audio -- 5 of 11 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0081)
        - Audio -- 6 of 11 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0082)
        - Audio -- 7 of 11 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0083)
        - Audio -- 8 of 11 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0084)
        - Audio -- 9 of 11 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0085)
        - Audio -- 10 of 11 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0086)
        - Audio -- 11 of 11 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0087)
    - Retrospective and Critical Examination of Orson Welles -- Poster, April 22-May 15, 1988 (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Martin Luther King, Jr. Conference, 1989-1990
      - Paper Records, 1989-1990 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Electronic Records, 1990; RG_9-5-1_ER_63
    - Choosing Lives/Limiting Lives--GTE Foundation, 1989-1990 (Box 27, Folder 18-19)
    - Choosing Lives: The Human Genome Project and Its Social Implication Symposium, 1990
      - Paper Records, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - Audio Recording, March 26, 1990 (Box Shared University Archives 151, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0236)
    - Limiting Lives: Rationing Life-Prolonging Technology Symposium, 1990
      - Paper Records, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Poster, 1990 (Box 88, Folder 8)
      - Audio Recording, April 1990 (Box 91, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0269)
    - Preparing for the 21st Century: A National Challenge for Higher Education Symposium, 1990
      - Paper Records, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 16)
      - Poster, 1990 (Box 88, Folder 9)
      - Audio Recordings, October 10, 1990
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0007)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 94, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0028)
    - Proposal for Presidential Symposia, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Representing Native Americans Conference -- Poster, April 2-4, 1992 (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - The State of Children: Children of the State Conference, 1992; RG_9-5-1_ER_70
    - Black Public Sphere: Toward an Ethnography of the Black Good Life and Society Conference, 1993
      - Paper Records, 1993 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Electronic Records, 1993; RG_9-5-1_ER_48
      - Poster, 1993 (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Deconstruction is/in America Conference -- Poster, October 7-8, 1993 (Box Shared University Archives 154, Folder 2)
    - Proposed Conference on Studies in Hysteria, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Subseries II.G: Other NYU Programming, 1978-1994; 1.75 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes, 1 half-manuscript box, and 4 folders in oversize flat boxes; 7 audiocassettes; 2 VHS; 3.48 Megabytes in 30 computer files
    Subseries II.G Other NYU Programming (dated 1978-1994) includes paper and electronic records and audio recordings documenting tributes, readings, exhibitions, and discussions facilitated by the Humanities Council. Several of the events documented by correspondence, logistical planning records, invitations, mailing lists, and audio recordings, but some are represented solely by event posters. One file, "God's Trombones: A Tribute to James Weldon Johnson," contains a video recording of the event.
    - Samuel Beckett Festival, 1978-1979 (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Samuel Beckett 75th Birthday Celebration at La MaMa Theater, 1981 (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - A Sesquicentennial Exhibition: New York University 1931-1981, 1981-1982
      - Poster, 1981-1982 (Box 88, Folder 9)
      - Paper Records, 1981-1982 (Box 87, Folder 3-4)
    - "The Literary Scene" Readings and Discussions, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Exhibition and Special Program for George Seferis, 1984
      - Paper Records, 1984 (Box 42, Folder 8, Box 43, Folder 1-2)
      - Electronic Records, 1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_49
    - An Homage to Michel Foucault -- Poster, March 27, 1985 (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - Screening of "The Good Fight: The Abraham Lincoln Brigade in the Spanish Civil War" -- Poster, March 15, 1986 (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - A Tribute to Samuel Beckett on His 80th Birtday, 1986
      - Paper Records, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 24)
      - Poster, 1986 (Box Shared University Archives 097, Folder 18)
    - M. L. Rosenthal: A Reading of His Poetic Works, April 28, 1987 (Box 93, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0089)
    - Reception for Soviet Film Makers, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Black Authors at NYU, February 23, 1989
      - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box Shared University Archives 151, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0231)
      - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box Shared University Archives 151, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0232)
    - Discussion "The African American Scholar: Choosing a Life of Learning", 1990
      - Paper Records, 1990 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Audio Recordings, February 22, 1990
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0261)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0262)
    - Jill Krementz Photography Exhibition "Literary Portraits", 1992 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Poetry Reading with Michael Harper, Sharon Olds, Galway Kinnell, 1992
      - Paper Records, 1992 (Box 35, Folder 18)
      - Electronic Records, 1992; RG_9-5-1_ER_66
      - Poster, 1992 (Box 88, Folder 1)
      - Audio Recording, 1992 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0113)
    - "God's Trombones:" A Tribute to James Weldon Johnson, November 4, 1992
      - Paper Records (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - Video Recordings, November 4, 1992
        - Video -- 1 of 2 (Box 76, Vhs 9-5-1.0002)
        - Video -- 2 of 2 (Box 76, Vhs 9-5-1.0003)
    - The Irish Muse: An Evening of Readings, 1993
      - Paper Records, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 19)
      - Electronic Records, 1993; RG_9-5-1_ER_68
      - Poster, 1993 (Box 88, Folder 9)
      - Audio Recording, April 27, 1993 (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0186)
    - Women's Voices in the Americas Readings, 1993
      - Paper Records, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 20)
      - Electronic Records, 1993; RG_9-5-1_ER_74
    - Ben Snow Room Exhibits, 1994; RG_9-5-1_ER_35
- Series III: Outside Programming, 1979-1989; 5.25 Linear Feet in 9 manuscript boxes, 1 half-manuscript box, and 3 folders in oversize flat boxes; 393 kilobytes in 69 computer files; 2 Quarter_Inch_Audio_Reel; 56 audiocassettes